foreign
[Music]
500 crore rupees socioeconomic
opportunity that has yet to be tapped a
recently released report by the India
welfare trust covered 100 large
companies across different sectors in
India it has shed light on volunteering
Trends with about 15 million White
Collar employees in India potential of
150 million plus hours can be
volunteered annually by corporate India
towards social and economic development
this could potentially create a
five-fold social return on investment
for companies let me now go across to
bhargav das Gupta MD and CEO at ICICI
Lombard General Insurance
co-founder and director at I volunteer
with us also is kartik Agarwal the
author of the report and growth
strategist at India welfare truster
subord bargov if I can begin with you
give us a sense of uh
Gupta if I can begin with you give us a
sense of the kind of volunteering
opportunities you're offering at ICICI
Lombard currently and how is it
important for the well-being of your
employees and the career of your
employees as well
uh thanks uh parikshit yeah this is
indeed a very uh interesting report that
we just got to see recently uh so at ICS
our volunteering initiative is called
caring hands
uh now this is something that has been
going on for about 11 years now uh back
in 2011 we felt that there was a uh you
know cap in terms of the healthcare uh
you know service that we could provide
to underprivileged schools children of
underprivileged schools and the approach
that we thought was uh would be have
would be uh do a hundred percent
employee volunteering you know it's easy
to just you know sign a check and hand
over to an NGO but we just felt that
this could be an initiative where we
involve our people and through that
process build certain uh you know
character traits in a sense you know
leadership traits within our people so
that was the thought process uh only
origin initially honestly we were not
sure whether it will uh it'll get a
buy-in but uh the experience that we had
in the first very first year was very
positive so what we did was we uh
selected uh a few schools usually BMC
schools you know schools uh for uh
slightly underprivileged children and we
uh ensured that we did Health camps in
these schools and over the years the the
entire initiative morphed to
specializing in in eye care because
that's something that we saw as a
massive Gap our data and our experience
shows that between 15 to 20 of the
children that we do a health checkup or
eye checkup Camp need some kind of
intervention maybe in terms of specs
maybe in terms of corrective surgery so
this is the whole effort that we do and
over the years over the last 11 years
we've covered about 400 000 children uh
every year roughly 25 to almost 40
percent of a staff on one single day
come together and run this volunteering
camps initially it was largely centrally
organized now centrally we just set up
the framework uh you know some
collaterals are centrally prepared but
the activity is completely uh owned and
executed by field teams on the ground so
in each branch eight to ten people come
together from a squad which goes out
goes to a school convinces the school
that this is a good idea and over the
years we've built the reputation and the
trust with these
I'm gonna come back to you
right I'm going to come back to you I'll
take quick questions with our other
pandas karte Agarwal is also joining us
uh Karthik now when it comes to extent
of volunteering activities how many
companies are making disclosures about
this and uh to what extent have they
been adopted by some of the top
companies in India
yeah thanks uh so you know we have seen
a lot of development in volunteering in
in companies in India over the last you
know last several years what we have
found which is very encouraging which
was the 78 of the companies that we
looked at did disclose some form of
volunteering or either informal programs
or activities that you know they are
offering to their employees uh but the
disclosure in terms of uh number of
volunteers per year or the number of
volunteering hours uh being done per
year uh you know I think there is room
for uh for growth there so we found that
26 of the companies are reporting annual
volunteers and 39 are reporting annual
volunteering hours so definitely when
you look at the number of companies that
that are currently supporting
volunteering there's definitely
opportunity there for more companies to
disclose uh volunteering information
right shalab when it comes to the kind
of volunteering activities that
corporates can offer what is a good way
to start what are some of the sectors uh
which are popular with Indian companies
uh well I would begin by saying that you
know the most popular sector tend to be
uh working with children on education
followed by an environment and then
health and elderly
um because these are the sectors that
espouse the maximum amount of empathy to
begin with but all causes are equally
important and I believe that when
volunteers start volunteering they they
endear to whatever cause that they begin
with uh to begin volunteering we always
say that no it's important to first
understand a particular cause so for
example it's important to not just Begin
by saying that I know best and I will
kind of go there and give a council on
what kind of quality needs to be done uh
what really works well is to kind of
embed the employees into a cause get
them to go and understand what a
non-profit does how a community faces a
particular Challenge and then in doing
so develop an empathy which leads to
longer term uh commitment we find that
when volunteering is a quick fix uh the
commitment goes missing so it takes a
lot of investment very early on in the
very stages into ensuring that employees
understand the cause developer connect
with the people that they're going to
volunteer with understand the challenges
that non-profits face and then can
definitely decide what kind of
volunteering path uh they will take so
uh that's a that's a quick way to start
all right my final question to bhargav
das Gupta bhagavadas Gupta give us a
sense of how ICICI and Lombard would
like to expand its volunteering
activities in future how many more
employees would you like to cover as
part of your program
um we just have about 30 seconds yeah
the entire approach that we have is a
completely voluntary we don't force
people to volunteer it's left to
individual uh individual team super
volunteer and as I said generally we
find on that particular day roughly
about 30 35 of our staff come together
and volunteer we are open as an
organization but we don't want to set
some targets for people to uh to decide
to volunteer
thank you so much for joining us talking
about the importance of volunteering
karthikey and shalab as well with that
it's a wrap on this edition of
NewsCenter more news and updates
continue right here
foreign
[Music]